export const md_problems_coaching = [
    {
        choices: ["10", "20", "40", "30"],
        correctAnswer: "40",
        question: "What pressure, in tons, is required to punch a hole 2&amp;amp;quot; diameter through a 1/4&amp;amp;quot; steel plate?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["333.0 mm", "330 mm", "330.3 mm", "303.3 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "303.3 mm",
        question: "Two shafts 3.6 m between centers carry pulleys 1.2 m in diameter and 0.91 m in diameter respectively, connected by a crossed belt. It is desired to put the belt on as an open belt. how long a piece must be cut of it?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["5 threads/inch", "2.5 threads/inch", "0.2 threads/inch", "10 threads/inch"],
        correctAnswer: "10 threads/inch",
        question: "The root diameter of a double square thread is 0.55 inch. The screw has a pitch of 0.2 inch. Find the number of thread per inch.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["254 mm", "245 mm", "452 mm", "425 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "245 mm",
        question: "A 75-mm diameter shaft is transmitting 350 kW at 650 rpm. A flange coupling is used and has 6 bolts, each 18 mm in diameter. Find the required diameter of the bolts circle based on an average shearing stress of 27.5 MPa.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.50 inch and 4 threads/inch", "0.75 inch and 4 threads/inch", "0.75 inch and 5 threads/inch", "0.50 inch and 5 threads/inch"],
        correctAnswer: "0.75 inch and 5 threads/inch",
        question: "The root diameter of a double square thread is 0.55 inch. The screw has a pitch of 0.2 inch. Find the outside diameter and the number of threads per inch.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1.418", "1.184", "1.148", "1.814"],
        correctAnswer: "1.184",
        question: "A helical-coil spring has a mean coil diameter of 1 inch and a wire diameter of 1/8 inch. Determine the Wahl factor of the spring.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["27.6", "25.0", "26.2", "32.4"],
        correctAnswer: "27.6",
        question: "A wire rope lifts a load of 10 kips at maximum speed of 1000 feet per minute, attained in 5 seconds starting from rest. The rope has a metallic cross sectional area of 0.44 in^2. Determine the maximum tensile stress on the rope in ksi.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["15.7 lb", "165.7 lb", "175.5 lb", "157.5 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "157.5 lb",
        question: "A flat belt is 6 inches wide and 1/3 inch thick and transmits 15 Hp. The center distance is 8 ft. The driving pulley is 6 inches diameter and rotates at 2000 rpm such that the loose side of the belt is on top. The driven pulley is 18 in. in diameter. The belt material is 0.035 lb/in^3 and the coefficient of friction is 0.30. Determine the belt net tension.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["200 pitches", "220 pitches", "216 pitches", "212 pitches"],
        correctAnswer: "212 pitches",
        question: "A 20-tooth motor sprocket, running at 1200 rpm, drives a blower at a speed ratio of 4:1. using the largest permissible chain sizeand the largest permissible center distance of 60 pitchesl, what length of chain in pitches is requird to connect the sprockets?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["6 mm/s", "5 mm/s", "5.5 mm/s", "7 mm/s"],
        correctAnswer: "6 mm/s",
        question: "A single square thread power screw is to raise a load of 70 kN. The screw has a major diameter of 36 mm and a pitch of 6 mm. The coefficient of thread friction and collar friction are 0.13 and 0.10 respectively. If the collar mean diameter is 90mm and the screw turns at 60 rpm, find the axial linear speed of the screw.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["25.74 Hp", "27.45 Hp", "24.75 Hp", "24.57"],
        correctAnswer: "25.74 Hp",
        question: "Determine the power capacity of a cone clutch under uniform pressure and assuming the following conditions major diameter = 250 mm; minor diameter = 200 mm; length of conical elements in contact = 125 mm; rotational speed = 870 rpm; coefficient of friction = 0.30; and allowable pressure = 70 kPa.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["26.6 mm", "25.6 mm", "16.6 mm", "24.6 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "26.6 mm",
        question: "A 20° involute spur gear has a tooth whole depth of 16.95 mm, a tooth thickness of 13.2 mm, and a pitch of 3. Determine the circular pitch of the gear.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["19.56", "21.65", "25.12", "16.95"],
        correctAnswer: "19.56",
        question: "Compute the nominal shear stress at the surface, in MPa, for a 50 mm diameter shaft that is subjected to a torque of 0.48 kN-m.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["20º", "20.5º", "18.4º", "14.5º"],
        correctAnswer: "18.4º",
        question: "A 20º straight-tooth bevel pinion having 14 teeth and a diametral pitch of 6 teeth/inch drives a 42-tooth gear. The two shafts are at right angles and in the same plane. Find the pitch angle of the pinion.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.43140 inch", "0.03140 inch", "0.31416 inch", "0.23140 inch"],
        correctAnswer: "0.31416 inch",
        question: "Compute the tooth thickness of a 14.5&amp;amp;#42; spur gear with diametral pitch of 5.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["7", "15", "10", "12"],
        correctAnswer: "10",
        question: "A solid shaft 150 mm in diameter is coupled by bolts 32 mm in diameter with centers 130 mm from the axis. How many bolts are necessary (assume same material for shaft and bolt).",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["47.2 Hp", "23.5 Hp", "35.2 Hp", "27.4 Hp"],
        correctAnswer: "47.2 Hp",
        question: "A disc clutch has 6 pairs of contracting friction surface with an outside diameter of 200 mm and an inside diameter of 100 mm. The coefficient of friction of the clutch materials is 0.4 and the axial force is 1500 N. The shaft speed is 1200 rpm. Determine the Hp that can be transmitted by the clutch assuming uniform pressure.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["88%", "93%", "60%", "80%"],
        correctAnswer: "80%",
        question: "Through bolt is used to fasten two plates with a gasket between two plates. It is known that the ratio of the deflection of the per nit load to the deflection of the bolted parts per unit is 1/4. WHat percentage of the applied load to the plates will added to the initial tightening load of the bolt?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["640", "520.4", "720", "425.3"],
        correctAnswer: "720",
        question: "Pulley A drives pulley B, Coupled to the shaft of B is pulley C which drives another puelly D. If puelly diameters are 18, 12, 24 and 13 inches, respectively for A,B,C, and D. Determine the rpm of D if the rpm of A is 260.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.25", "0.33", "0.22", "0.38"],
        correctAnswer: "0.25",
        question: "Determine the Possion&amp;amp;#39;s ratio of a material whose modulus of elasticity is 200 GPa and whose modulus of rigidity is 80 GPa.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["3.6 inches", "5.3 inches", "6.3 inches", "4.3 inches"],
        correctAnswer: "6.3 inches",
        question: "A 101.6 mm shaft using a flat key, whose width is 25.4 mm, is transmitting a torque of 63 000 in-lb. If the design shearing stress is 5000 psi, determine the safe length of key.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["87.97%", "86.55%", "84.58%", "85.66%"],
        correctAnswer: "87.97%",
        question: "A 20-kW motor, running at 1200 rpm, drives a 400 mm diameter pulley at a belt tension ratio of 2.4. If the belt&amp;amp;#39;s tight side tension is only 1200 N, determine the transmission efficiency.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["17.25 cm", "19.25 cm", "20.25 cm", "18.25 cm"],
        correctAnswer: "19.25 cm",
        question: "If two parallel shafts are connected by cylinders in pure rolling contact and turning in the same direction, and having a speed ratio of 2.75, what is the center distance of the two shafts assuming that the diameter of the smaller cylinder is 22 cm?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["4.69º", "6.49º", "6.94", "9.46º"],
        correctAnswer: "9.46º",
        question: "A double-thread worm has a pitch diameter of 3 inches. The wheel has 20 teeth and a pitch diameter of 5 inches. Find the gear helix angle.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["11.5", "19.5", "13.5", "15.5"],
        correctAnswer: "19.5",
        question: "The load on a helical spring is 1600 lb and the corresponding deflection is to be 4 inches. Rigidity modulus is 11 x 10^4 psi and the maximum intensity of safe torsional stress is 60,000 psi. IF the wire diameter and the mean diameter are 0.625 in and 3 in respectively. Determine the number of active coils.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["288", "204", "120", "144"],
        correctAnswer: "288",
        question: "What is the slenderness ratio of a 72-inch long, 1-inch diameter rod if it has fixed ends?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["150", "368", "1474", "38"],
        correctAnswer: "1474",
        question: "A flywheel weighing 457 kg has a radius of 375 mm. How uch energy, in N-m, does the flywheel loss from 3 rps to 2.8 rps?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["13.08 mm", "10.08 mm", "12.08 mm", "11.08 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "12.08 mm",
        question: "A 50-mm diameter shaft is to transmit 12 kW power at a speed of 500 rpm, determine the mean diameter of the pin, under double shear, for material having a safe unit stress of 40 N/mm^2.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["5 mm/s", "5.5 mm/s", "7 mm/s", "6 mm/s"],
        correctAnswer: "6 mm/s",
        question: "A single square thread power screw is to raise a load of 70 kN. The screw has a major diameter of 36 mm and a pitch of 6 mm.The coefficient of thread friction and a collar friction are 0.13 and 0.10 respectively. If the collar mean diameter is 90 mm and the screw turns at 60 rpm, find teh axial linear speed of the screw.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["7.62 inches", "6.27 inches", "7.26 inches", "6.72 inches"],
        correctAnswer: "6.72 inches",
        question: "A triple-thread worm has a lead angle of 17º and a pitch diameter of 2.2802 inches. Find the center distance when the worm is mated with a wheel of 48 teeth.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["618.5 lb", "817.2 lb", "702.2 lb", "537.2 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "618.5 lb",
        question: "A thrust washer has an inside diameter of 0.5 inch and an outside diameter of 3 inches. For an allowable bearing pressure of 90 psi, how much axial load can it sustain?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2.33 inches and 2.33 inches", "3.23 inches and 3.56 inches", "2.33 inches and 5.36 inches", "5.36 inches and 6.36 inches"],
        correctAnswer: "2.33 inches and 5.36 inches",
        question: "A 20º straight-tooth bevel pinion having 14 teeth and a diametral pitch of 6 teeth/inch drives a 32-tooth gear. The two shafts are at right angles and in the same plane. The pinion is to transmit 1800 rpm and transmitting 50 hp. Determine the pitch diameters of the gears.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["408.6 mm", "486.0 mm", "460.8 mm", "480.6 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "408.6 mm",
        question: "Two extension coil springs are hooked in series that support a single weight of 100 kg. The first spring is rated at 4 kN/m and the other spring is rated at 6 kN/m. Determine the total deflection of the springs.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1.6526 inches/tooth", "1.6256 inches/tooth", "1.6625 inches/tooth", "1.2566 inches/tooth"],
        correctAnswer: "1.2566 inches/tooth",
        question: "A parallel helical gear set was a 17-tooth pinion driving a 34-tooth gear. The pinion has a right-hand helix angle of 30º, and a normal diametral pitch of 5 teeth/in. Find the axial circular pitches.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["205.9 cm^4", "205.9 cm^3", "209.5 cm^4", "209.5 cm^3"],
        correctAnswer: "205.9 cm^3",
        question: "What is the polar section modulus of solid shaft with a diameter of 101.6 mm?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["10.13", "13.11º", "11.13º", "11.31º"],
        correctAnswer: "11.31º",
        question: "A triple threaded worm has a pitch diameter of 3 inches. The wheel has 25 teeth and a pitch diameter of 5 inches. Material from both the wheel and the wheel is phosphor bronze. Determine the helix angle of the gear.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["150 ksi", "75 ksi", "300 ksi", "200 ksi"],
        correctAnswer: "150 ksi",
        question: "A steel has a BHN = 300. What is its approximate ultimate strength in ksi?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.34 deg", "1.31 deg", "0.84 deg", "0.53 deg"],
        correctAnswer: "0.84 deg",
        question: "A power of 25 KW at 150 mm is availabe on a distributed line shaft of 6.35 cm dia. Two pulleys mounted on the shaft for power distribution, 45, 72, cm apart, tend to cause torsional deflection. Shear modulus of elasticity 75.02 GPa. Which of the following values most nearly equal to the angle of twist in the shaft between the pulley?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["48.22%", "34.32%", "55.12%", "30.32%"],
        correctAnswer: "30.32%",
        question: "The efficiency of a 2&amp;amp;quot; screw with a TPI of 2 (single thread, square-form) whose coefficient of friction is 0.2 is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2803 rpm", "2380 rpm", "2308 rpm", "2038 rpm"],
        correctAnswer: "2038 rpm",
        question: "A 1-inch diameter shaft has a single disc weighing 75 lb mounted midway between two bearings 20&amp;amp;quot; apart. Find the lowest critical speed in rpm. Neglect the weight of the shaft. Assume that the modulus of elasticity is 30 x 10^6 psi.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["14.2 ft", "12.4 ft", "18.6 ft", "16.8 ft"],
        correctAnswer: "14.2 ft",
        question: "What is the maximum allowable length between supports for a 2inch diameter shaft that has no bending load except its own weight?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["5.5 mm", "3.3 mm", "8.8 mm", "4.4 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "4.4 mm",
        question: "With the water interruptions prevailing in your town, you have been asked to design an upright cylindrical water tank 6 meters in diameter and 6 meters high, vented, and to be filled completely with water. Determine the minimum thickness of the tank plate if the stress is limited to 40 MPa.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["35, 450 lb", "65, 240 lb", "45, 567 lb", "54, 623 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "45, 567 lb",
        question: "The distance between the adjacent threds on a triple-threaded screw of a square thread form is 2/3 inch. The mean radius is inches. The coefficient of friction is 0.10. What load can be by exerting a moment of 2000 ft-lb?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2.5 inches", "2.75 inches", "5.3 inches", "2.3 inches"],
        correctAnswer: "2.75 inches",
        question: "THe shaft is subjected to a stedy load of 36,000 lbs at a shear stress of 10,000 Psi. Compute the diameter of the said shaft in inches.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["5.85 mm", "8.85 mm", "6.85 mm", "7.85 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "6.85 mm",
        question: "A hollow iron pipe to be designed as a column has an outside diameter of 240 mm and is subjected to a force of 80 kN. Find the pipe thickness if the compressive stress is limited 16 MPa.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["33.97 in-lb", "39.73 in-lb", "39.37 in-lb", "37.93 in-lb"],
        correctAnswer: "37.93 in-lb",
        question: "A vise is equipped with a 1-inch single square thread, with 4 threads per inch. The frictional radius of the collar is 0.5 inch. The coefficient of friction for both the collar and threads is 0.20. How much external torque must be applied to produce a force of 200 lb against the jaws of the vise?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["L = 0.87 D", "L = 3.15 D", "L = 1.51 D", "L = 2.45 D"],
        correctAnswer: "L = 1.51 D",
        question: "A square key has a breadth equal to one-fourth of the shaft diameter. The shaft and key are of materials that are equally strong with a yield point value in shear equal to one-half the yield point value in tension. Find the required length of the key in terms of shaft diameter necessary the shaft torque.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["3 950 lb", "3 600 lb", "3 800 lb", "3 900 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "3 900 lb",
        question: "Compute the working strength of 1 inch bolt which is screwed up tightly in packed joint when the allowable working stress is 13000 psi.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["53 000 N", "60 000 N", "42 000 N", "52 840 N"],
        correctAnswer: "52 840 N",
        question: "What load in N must be applied to a 25 mm round steel bar 2.5 m long (E = 207 GPa) to streth the bar 1.3mm?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["5 mm/s", "6 mm/s", "7 mm/s", "5.5 mm/s"],
        correctAnswer: "6 mm/s",
        question: "A single square thread power screw is to raise a load of 70 kN. The screw has a major diameter of 36 mm and a pitch of 6 mm.The coefficient of thread friction and a collar friction are 0.13 and 0.10 respectively. If the collar mean diameter is 90 mm and the screw turns at 60 rpm, find teh axial linear speed of the screw.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1.5 and 57.99 mm²", "0.555 and 57.99 mm²", "0.667 and 57.99 mm²", "1.75 and 57.99 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "0.667 and 57.99 mm²",
        question: "What is the number of threads per mm and the tensile stress area of a stranded Metric screw Thread designated by M10 x 1.5?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["8.4", "4.8", "4.08", "6.4"],
        correctAnswer: "4.08",
        question: "What is the friction radius of a clutch disk, in cm, having an outside diamter of 100 mm and an inner diameter of 60mm.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["333.7 lb", "733.3 lb", "373.3 lb", "337.3 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "333.7 lb",
        question: "A flywheel has a mean diameter of 4 ft and is required to handle 2250 ft-lb of kinetic energy. It has a width of 8 inhes, mean operating speed is 300 rpm and the coefficient of fluctuation is to be 0.5. Find the weight of rim, assuming that the arms and hub are equivalent to 10% of the total rim weight. The flywheel is made up of cast iron with specific weight of 0.26 lb per cubic inch.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["5.287", "2.857", "5.782", "2.578"],
        correctAnswer: "2.578",
        question: "A pulley 600 mm in diameter transmits 40 kW at 500 rpm. The arc of contact between the belt and pulley is 155º, the coefficient of friction between belt and puelly is 0.35 and the safe working stress of the belt is 2.1 MPa. Determine the belt tensions ratio, neglecting the effect of centrifugal force.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2356 N-m", "3265 N-m", "6325 N-m", "5236 N-m"],
        correctAnswer: "2356 N-m",
        question: "A solid disk flywheel has a diameter of 1.5m, and a mass of 800 kg. What torque is need to produc ean angular acceleration of 100 revolutions per minute, per second?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["222.34 mm", "23.42 cm", "24.22 cm", "234.22 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "222.34 mm",
        question: "If the angular deformation of a solid shaft should not exceed 1º in a length of a 1.8 m and the allowable shearing stress is 83 MMa, what is the diameter of the shaft? Assume that the shaft material has G = 77 x 10 ^6 kPa.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["12.87 mm", "14.89 mm", "18.23 mm", "16.56 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "16.56 mm",
        question: "A thin walled cylindrical pressure vessel, 1.5 inches in diameter, subjected to an internal pressure which varies from 690 kPa to 450 kPa, continuously. Find the required thickness in mm of the wall based on a yield point of 480 MPa, net endurance strength of 20 MPa and a factor of safety of 2.0.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.08900 inch", "0.0899 inch", "0.09000 inch", "0.089758 inch"],
        correctAnswer: "0.08900 inch",
        question: "Determine the minimum whole depth of spur gear of 14.5º involute type with diametral pitch of 24 and circular pitch of 0.1309 inch.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["15.0 MPa", "16.4 Mpa", "12.2 Mpa", "10.2 Mpa"],
        correctAnswer: "10.2 Mpa",
        question: "Determine the maximum stress in a hollow column of D = 160 mm, and D = 100mm that supports a load of 40 kN and a benidng moment of 4 kN-m.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["36", "30", "24", "48"],
        correctAnswer: "48",
        question: "A set of bevel gears in a vehicle differentials has a 4&amp;amp;quot; pitch dimaeter pinion whose pitch angle is 18.43°. For a diametral pitch of 4, edetermine the number of teeth of the larger gear.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["305.57", "70.42", "127", "402.73"],
        correctAnswer: "305.57",
        question: "An air cylinder has bore of 25 mm and is operated with shop air of a pressure of 90 psi. Find the push force exerted by the piston rod in N.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["446 ft/s", "234 ft/s", "436 ft/s", "346 ft/s"],
        correctAnswer: "436 ft/s",
        question: "From 26th Machinery&amp;amp;#39;s Handbook, the bursting speed for flywheel has an empirical formula of F = sqrt(10) - 4 Where: v = ft/s and S = strength of rim material in pouds per in². Thus, for cast iron having a tensile strength of 19,000 pounds per square inch the bursting speed would be:                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.0357 inch", "0.75 inch", "0.083 inch", "0.5 inch"],
        correctAnswer: "0.0357 inch",
        question: "What is the pitch of an American Standard Screw with designation 12-28 UNF?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["45 rpm", "90 rpm", "60 rpm", "75 rpm"],
        correctAnswer: "90 rpm",
        question: "A 36-tooth pinion turning at 300 rpm drives 120-tooth gear of 14.5º involute full depth pressure angle. Determine the rpm of the driven gear.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["8.97 mm", "1.54 mm", "5.7 mm", "2.43 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "5.7 mm",
        question: "Two diagonal aluminum alloy tension rods 15 mm in diameter are used in a rectangular to prevent collapse. The rods can safely spport a tensile stress of 135 Mpa. If the rods are initially 3m in length, how much must they be sketched to develop this stress? E = 71 GPa.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["6790", "3900", "3098", "7660"],
        correctAnswer: "7660",
        question: "A spur pinion rotates at 600 rpm and transmits 25 kW to a mating gear. the pitch diameter of the pinion is 100 mm, and the pressure angle is 20º. Determine the tangential load, in N.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.3714 Hp", "0.7314 Hp", "0.4713 Hp", "0.4371 Hp"],
        correctAnswer: "0.3714 Hp",
        question: "Determinet he Hp lost when a collar is loaded with 2000 lb, rotates at 50 rpm, and has a coefficient of friction of 0.15. The outside diameter of the collar is 4 inches and the inside diameter is 2 inches.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["46 x 10^6 psi", "45 x 10^6 psi", "40 x 10^6 psi", "43 x 10^6 psi"],
        correctAnswer: "43 x 10^6 psi",
        question: "What modulus of elasticity in tension is required to obtain a unit of deformation of 0.00105 from a load producing a unit tensile stress of 31263.27 kg/cm^2?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["223 N", "238 N", "328 N", "332 N"],
        correctAnswer: "332 N",
        question: "A cone clutch has an angle of 9 degrees and a coefficient of friction of 42. Find the axial force required if the capacity of the clutch is kW at 500 rpm. The mean diameter of the active conical sections is 300mm. Use the uniform wear method.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["36.8 N", "30.5 N", "35.7 N", "33.4 N"],
        correctAnswer: "33.4 N",
        question: "A shaft is connected with a coupling has elements with outside and inside of 250 mm and 100 mm respectively,. The axial force is 1200 N. If the coefficient of friction is 0.3, find the capacity of the coupling.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["102 lb", "120 lb", "201 lb", "210 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "210 lb",
        question: "A flat belt is 6 inches wide and 1/3 inch thick and transmits 20 Hp. The center distance is 8 ft. The driving pulley is 6 inches in diameter and rotates at 2 000 rpm such that the loose side of the belt is on top. The driven pulley is 18 inches in diameter. The belt material is 0.035 lb/in^3 and the coefficient of friction is 0.30. Determine the belt net tension.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["15.97%", "13.52%", "15.32%", "12.53%"],
        correctAnswer: "12.53%",
        question: "A single square thread power screw is to raise a load of 70 kN. The screw has a major diameter of 36 mm and a pitch of 6 mm. The coefficient of thread friction and collar friction are 0.13 and 0.10 respectively. If the collar mean diameter is 90 mm and the screw turns at 60 rpm, find the combined efficiency of the screw and collar?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["9.085 x 10^-5 in^2", "9.085 x 10^-4 in^2", "9.085 x 10^-2 in^2", "9.085 x 10^-3 in^2"],
        correctAnswer: "9.085 x 10^-3 in^2",
        question: "Determine the tensile stress area of an American Standard Screw threads 6-32 UNC with basic major diameter of 0.1380 inch.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["20,200", "20,120 ", "20,100", "20,400"],
        correctAnswer: "20,400",
        question: "What is the working strength, in lbs, of a 2&amp;amp;quot; bolt which is screwered up tightly in a packeted joint when the allowable working stress is 17,000 psi?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["6.06 inches", "2.06 inches", "4.04 inches", "2.02 inches"],
        correctAnswer: "4.04 inches",
        question: "A parallel helical gear-set consists of a 19-tooth pinion driving a 57-teeth gear. The pinion has a left-hand helix angle of 20º, a normal pressure angle of 14 1/2º, and a normal diametral pitch of 10 teeth/inch. If the pinion is to transmit 50 Hp at speed of 1750 rpm. Determine the center distance of the two gears.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["205 mm", "305.4 mm", "405.2 mm", "203.2 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "203.2 mm",
        question: "A slider crank mechanism consists of crank Q2A = 100 mm, link B = 300 mm , and block B. If crank Q2A&amp;amp;#39;s axis is located 50 km above the horizontal line of action of the slider, determine the stroke of the block.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2100 mr", "1200 mr", "20100 mr", "2001 mr"],
        correctAnswer: "20100 mr",
        question: "Selecting a deep-groove ball bearing to carry a radial load Fx = 800 lb and a thrust load Fz = 700 lb at 1750 rpm. The service is 8 hr/day, but it is not continuous; design for 20 000 hr. The operation is smooth with little vibration; the outer ring rotates. Determine the design life in mr with no more than 10% failure.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["51.55 mm", "65.15 mm", "55.15 mm", "61.55 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "55.15 mm",
        question: "A vertical steel cylinder water tank is 30 m in diameter and 45 m high. The allowable stress of the steel plate is 1224 kg/cm². Without reinforcing angle bars and rods, what is the thickness of the steel plate?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2.77 inches", "4.77 inches", "1.77 inches", "3.77 inches"],
        correctAnswer: "4.77 inches",
        question: "A steam engine that has a stroke of 12 inches has an overhung crank of 11 inches. The maximum tangential force, P, on the crank may be assumed as 75000 lb. Assuming an allowable stress in shear as 4400 psi, determine the crankshaft diameter.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["987.6 N", "2456.3 N", "1390.2 N", "3819.6 N"],
        correctAnswer: "1390.2 N",
        question: "A pinion 100 mm in diameter is transmitting 10 kW at 500 rpm. This gear is in mesh with another 250mm-diameter gear. If the pressure angle is 20°, determine the separating force between the pair of gears.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["48.6 kN-m", "64.3 kN-m", "52.5 kN-m", "32.4 kN-m"],
        correctAnswer: "52.5 kN-m",
        question: "A 10 m simply supported beam has a 25 kN load 3 m from the left end. Find the maximum moment of the beam.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2 265 rpm", "2 182 rpm", "2 071 rpm", "2 341 rpm"],
        correctAnswer: "2 265 rpm",
        question: "Compute the speed of the gear mounted on a 52.5mmm diameter shaft receiving power from a driving motor with 250 Hp.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.0063", "0.0073", "0.0037", "0.00013"],
        correctAnswer: "0.0073",
        question: "A steel shaft 1.75 inches in diameter transmits 40 Hp at 1800 rpm. Assuming a modulus of rigidity of 12 x 10^5 psi, find the torsional deflection of the shaft in degrees per foot length.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2428 lb", "2820 lb", "3638 lb", "5460 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "3638 lb",
        question: "A multiple-disk clutch, composed of the three plates with a small diameter of 150 mm and large diameter of 200 mm, is designed to transmit 100 kw at 3000 rpm at a coefficient of friction of 0.5. Determine the spring force needed to engage the clutch.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["84.67", "46.87", "64.87", "74.64"],
        correctAnswer: "64.87",
        question: "The transmitted torque of a hollow shaft is 3400 N-m at a shearing stress of 55 MPa. If the oustide diameter is 1.25 times that of the inside diameter, what ist he isnide diameter in mm?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1.1144", "1.44", "1.144", "1.1414"],
        correctAnswer: "1.1144",
        question: "A helical-coil spring has a mean coil diameter of 1 inch and a wire diameter of 1/8 inch. Determine the curve correction factor of the spring.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["456.42 N-m", "497.85 N-m", "546.43 N-m", "597.84 N-m"],
        correctAnswer: "497.85 N-m",
        question: "A round steel rotates at 200 rpm and is subjected to a torque of 275 N-m and a bending moment of 415 N-m. Determine the equivalent twisting moment.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["40 mm", "30 mm", "50 mm", "20 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "30 mm",
        question: "The energy required to punch a square hole 20mm thick plate is 10 kJ. If the ultimate shear strength of the plate is 415 MPa, determine the maximum side of the square that can be punched.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["510 mm", "605 mm", "473 mm", "332 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "332 mm",
        question: "A flywheel has a rim weight of 450 kg and a mean radius of 450 mm, If the rim weidth is five times the rim thickness and material density is 7200 kg/m^3, determine the width of the rim.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["3 Hp", "18 Hp", "10 Hp", "7.1 Hp"],
        correctAnswer: "10 Hp",
        question: "What Hp can a 1-inch diameter short shaft transmit at 380 rpm?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["15.462º", "16.452", "14.265º", "12.465º"],
        correctAnswer: "12.465º",
        question: "A double thread ACME screw driven by a motor at 400 rpm raises the attached load of 900 kg at a speed of 10m/min. The screw has a pitch diameter of 36 mm;the coefficient of friction on threads is 0.15. The friction torque on the thrust bearing of the motor is taken as 20% of the total input. Determine the lead angle.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2.18 inches", "3.18 inches", "3.28 inches", "2.28 inches"],
        correctAnswer: "2.28 inches",
        question: "Line shaft is to transmit 299 Hp at 900 rpm. Find the diameter of the shaft.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["3.71 kN/m", "2.71 kN/m", "1.71 kN/m", "5 kN/m"],
        correctAnswer: "1.71 kN/m",
        question: "Three extension springs are hooked in series that support a single weight of 100 kg. The first spring is rated at 4 kN/m and the other two springs are rated 6 kN/m each. Determine the equivalent stiffness of the three springs.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["8.80", "12.30", "31.54", "19.93"],
        correctAnswer: "31.54",
        question: "A piston rod of an air operated press has a length of 760 mm, with its right hand end pin connected to the operating lever and the piston end of the rod fix ended. The rod is made of a material whos Sy = 250 Mpa and E = 200 Gpa. For a factor of safety of 2.5, determine the maximum safe compressive load of the rod in kN if its diameter is 20 mm.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["10.12 mm", "17.1 mm", "21.09 mm", "19.20 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "17.1 mm",
        question: "A shaft of 50 mm diameter is to transmit power of 12 kilowatts of a speed of 500 rpm, find the mean diameter of the pin for a material having a safe unit stress of 40 N/mm²",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.0 kg-m", "60 kg-m", "4800 kg-m", "3760 kg-m"],
        correctAnswer: "3760 kg-m",
        question: "A uniform beam 12 meters long is fixed at one end. It has a uniform weight of 50 kg/m along its length. A load of 20 kgs. is suspended on the beam 4 m from the free end. The moment at the fixed end is.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["490 psi", "904 psi", "940 psi", "409 psi"],
        correctAnswer: "490 psi",
        question: "If a sleeve bearing has an outside diameter of 38.1 mm and a length of 50.8 mm, the wall thickness is 3/16 inch. The bearing is subjected to a radial load of 500 kg. What is the bearing pressure, in psi?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["142 mm", "412 mm", "124 mm", "241 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "241 mm",
        question: "A right-handed single-thread hardened-steel worm has a catalog rating of 2.25 kW at 650 rpm when meshed with a 48-tooth cast-steel gear. The axial pitch of the worm is 25 mm, normal pressure angle is 14.5º, and the pitch diameter of the worm is 100 mm. the coefficient of friction is 0.085. Determine the shafts center distance.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.78 HP", "0.68 HP", "0.88 HP", "0.98 HP"],
        correctAnswer: "0.78 HP",
        question: "A 1.75 inch-diameter shaft is supported by two sleeve bearings. The total load on the two bearings is 2800 lb. Find the friction power loss, in HP, if the coefficient of friction between shaft and bearing is 0.10 and the shaft rotates 200 rpm.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.4371 Hp", "0.7314 Hp", "0.3714 Hp", "0.4713 Hp"],
        correctAnswer: "0.3714 Hp",
        question: "Determine the HP lost when a collar is loaded with 2000 lb, rotates at 50 rpm, and has a coefficient of friction of 0.15. The outside diameter of the collar is 4 inches and the inside diameter is 2 inches.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2820 N", "5460 N", "3638 N", "2428 N"],
        correctAnswer: "3638 N",
        question: "A multiple-disk clutch, composed of three plates with a small diameter of 150 mm and large diameter of 200 mm, is deisgned to transmit 100 kW at 3000 rpm at a coefficient of friction 0.5. Determine the spring force needed to engage the clutch.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["35 teeth", "33 teeth", "34 teeth", "30 teeth"],
        correctAnswer: "35 teeth",
        question: "A roller chain and sprocket is to drive vertical centrifugal discharge bucket elevator. The pitch of chain connecting sprockets is 1.75&amp;amp;quot; The driving sprocket is rotating at 120 rpm and has 11 teeth while the driven sprocket is rotating at 38 rpm. Determine the number of teeth of driven sprocket.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["18.4º", "20.5", "14.5º", "20º"],
        correctAnswer: "18.4º",
        question: "A 20º straight-tooth bevel pinion having 14 teeth and a diametral pitch of 6 teeth/inch drives a 42-tooth gear. The two shafts are at right angles and in the same plane. Find the pitch angle of the pinion.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1/1", "9/16", "1/2", "15/16"],
        correctAnswer: "15/16",
        question: "Two circular shafts, one hollow and one solid, are made of the same materials and have the diameters D and D/2 (DI), respectively. If Th is the torsional moment othat the hollow shaft can resist and Ts is the torsional moment that the solid shaft can resist, the ratio of Th to Ts is                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["3.3 sec", "0.9 sec", "0.12 sec", "3.7 sec"],
        correctAnswer: "3.3 sec",
        question: "An object is dropped from the floor approximately 55 meters above the concrete floor. How long in seconds, does it take to hit the floor?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1100", "1300", "900", "1500"],
        correctAnswer: "1100",
        question: "A 36-inch wide conveyor belt feeder having a speed of 750 ft/min moves a 205 kg of magnetite concentrates. Determine the developed kinetic energy in ft-lbs of the materials.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["5.6 cm", "4.5 cm", "3.87 cm", "4.5 cm"],
        correctAnswer: "3.87 cm",
        question: "Determine the length of a square key for a gear-driven shaft to withstand a torque of 1450 N-m. The shaft diameter is 65mm with a design stress of 72.6 MPa in shear. The thickness and width of key is 5.8 inch.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["52", "42", "58", "49"],
        correctAnswer: "52",
        question: "A fast truck is travelling in the highway at a velocity of 25 m/s. If it is decelerating at a rate of 6 m/sec/sec, how far, in meters, does it travel before stopping?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["8957 N", "7546 N", "9550 N", "8579 N"],
        correctAnswer: "9550 N",
        question: "AN electric motor drives a pump through a gear drive. The center distance is 120mm. The speed of the motor and the pump are 1500 rpm and 300 rpm respectively. If the pump requires a power input of 3kW. What is the tangential force on the gear teeth.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["11 kN/m", "9 kN/m", "15 kN/m", "10 kN/m"],
        correctAnswer: "10 kN/m",
        question: "The extension springs are hooked in parallel that suppor t a single weight of 100 kg. The springs are rated 4 kN/m, 5 kN/m and 6 kN/m., respectively. Determine the equivalent of the three springs.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["160.05 lbs", "163.85 lbs", "145.23 ", "155.235 lbs"],
        correctAnswer: "160.05 lbs",
        question: "Two pulleys 2-ft in diameter are connnected by a belt so that ,each has a belt wrapped around half of its circumference. The coefficient of friction between the belt and the pulley is 0.20. If the tension in tight side is 300 lbs, determien the tension in the slack side when the belt is about to slip.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["14.2", "23.15", "22.1", "14.73"],
        correctAnswer: "14.73",
        question: "Calculate the shear stress in MPa induced in a welded lap joint using two 60 mm long fillet welds, each having a leg of 8 mm. If the applied tensile load is 10 kN.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["60 Hp", "80 Hp", "50 Hp", "70 Hp"],
        correctAnswer: "60 Hp",
        question: "A small vehicle is designed to carry a load of 1000 lb at a speed of 8 miles per hour. If the empty vehicle weighs 600 lb, determine the engine horsepower required to move the vehicle horizontally. Use an over-all efficiency of 30% and a coefficient of friction of 0.5.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["911.0 MPa", "90.11 MPa", "91.10 MPa", "19.10 Mpa"],
        correctAnswer: "19.10 Mpa",
        question: "A cylinder having an internal diameter of 508 mm and external diameter of 914.4 mm is subjected to an internal pressure of 69 MPa and an external pressure of 14 MPa. Determine the hoop stress at the inner surface of the cylinder.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["56.6%", "65.6%", "60.6%", "50.6%"],
        correctAnswer: "56.6%",
        question: "A hollow shaft 12.7 cm outside dia. is used instead of a solid shaft of 9.652 cm dia. which has equal torsional strength. Calculate the percentage by weight of the material saved.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["141.42 kip", "200.02 kip", "100.02 kip", "70.71 kip"],
        correctAnswer: "70.71 kip",
        question: "Two overlapping 5/8&amp;amp;quot; thick steel plates are welded with two 5/8&amp;amp;quot; fillet welds, 3&amp;amp;quot; long, arranged normal to a load. Considering a design stress of 10 kal for the welds, calculate the maximum permissible load F on the plates.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["262.35", "61.95", "122.85", "362.25"],
        correctAnswer: "362.25",
        question: "If the coefficient of fluctuation is 0.1 and the motion speed of the flywheel is 1200 fpm, calculate the weight of the flywheel in lb. needed to store 450 ft-lb of energy.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1.271", "1.712", "1.172", "1.217"],
        correctAnswer: "1.172",
        question: "A helical-coil spring has a mean coil diameter of 1 inch and a wire diameter of 1/8 inch. Determine the value of bergstrassar factor of the spring.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["61 580 lb", "65 810 lb", "60 185 lb", "61 850 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "61 850 lb",
        question: "If the ultimate shear strength of a steel plates is 42 000 psi, what force is necessary to punch a 0.75 inch diameter hole in a 0.625 inch thick plate?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["27, 220 psi", "62, 237 psi", "14, 422 psi", "21, 760 psi"],
        correctAnswer: "21, 760 psi",
        question: "The maximum shear stress induced on a 1.5&amp;amp;quot; diameter solid shaft loaded with a torque of 8,000 in-lb and a bending moment 12,000 in-lb is;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["45.06 MPa", "36.84 MPa", "46.05 MPa", "38.64 MPa"],
        correctAnswer: "46.05 MPa",
        question: "A stepped torsion shaft has diameters of 16 mm and 12 mm and a fillet radius of 2 mm. The sahft is subjected to a torque of 12.5 N-m. Find the maximum induced stress caused by the fillet. Consider a stress concentration factor of 1.25.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["4.12", "1.24", "2.41", "2.14"],
        correctAnswer: "2.41",
        question: "A pulley 600 mm in diameter transmits 40 kW at 500 rpm. The ar of contact between the belt and pulley is 144°, the coefficient of friction between the belt and pulley is 0.35, and the safe working stress of the belt is 2.1 MPa. Determine the belt tensions ratio, neglecting the effect of centrifugal force.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["58.83 kW", "71.35 kW", "82.64 kW", "63.45 KW"],
        correctAnswer: "63.45 KW",
        question: "A line connection in an automobile transmission consists of lines cut in a 58mm diameter shaft. The height of each is 5.5mm and the keyways in the hub are 45mm long. Determine the power that maybe transmitted at 2500 rpm If the able normal pressure on the splines is limited to 4.8 Mpa.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["38.44 mm", "44.38 mm", "84.33 mm", "34.83 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "44.38 mm",
        question: "A shaft is simultaneously loaded with a torque of 900 N-m and a bending load of 4000 N applied at the center of its 500 mm span. Considering a maximum shear design stress of 60 MPa, determine the shaft diameter.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2.8 inches", "3.2 inches", "4.2 inches", "2.1 inches"],
        correctAnswer: "2.1 inches",
        question: "What length of a square key is required for a 4-in diameter shaft transmitting 1000 hp at 1000 rpm? The allowable shear and compressive stresses in the key are 15 ksi and 30 ksi, respectively.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["274.7 mm", "247.7 mm", "477.2 mm", "227.4 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "227.4 mm",
        question: "A 75-mm dimaeter shaft is transmitting 300 kW at 600 rpm. A flange coupling is used and has 6 bolts, each 18 mm in diameter. Find the required diameter of the bolts circle based on an average shearing stress of 27.5 MPa.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["51", "45", "48", "55"],
        correctAnswer: "48",
        question: "Using a oxyacetylene welding method to weld a 3 ft long seam in 3/8 in. thick steel plate at a consumption rate of 9 cu.ft/ft of acid for oxygen and 7 cu.ft/ft for acetylene. What is the total combined gas consumption in cubic feet.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["4 200 psi", "2 400 psi", "2 040 psi", "4 020 psi"],
        correctAnswer: "4 200 psi",
        question: "What is the bursting steam pressure of a hemispherical steel shell with a diameter of 100 inches and made of 0.0635-m thick steel plate, if the join efficiency is 70% and the tensile strength is 60 000 psi?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["68,488 ft-lb", "84,448 ft-lb", "53,123 ft-lb", "42,248 ft-lb"],
        correctAnswer: "68,488 ft-lb",
        question: "A 48-inch diameter spoked steel flywheel ([] = 0.28 lb/in^3) having a 12-in wide x 10 -in deep rim rotates at 1200 rpm. Determine the kinetic energy of this flywheel. Neglect the weight of its spokes and hub                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.4371 Hp", "0.4713 Hp", "0.3714 Hp", "0.7314 Hp"],
        correctAnswer: "0.3714 Hp",
        question: "Determine the HP lost when a collar is loaded with 2000 lb, rotates at 50 rpm, and has a coefficient of friction of 0.15. The outside diameter of the collar is 4 inches and the inside diameter is 2 inches.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["11 005 lb", "11 050 lb", "10 015 lb", "10 501 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "10 501 lb",
        question: "A 1200 mm cast iron pulley is fastened to 112.5 mm shaft by means of a 28.13 mm square key 175 mm long. The key and shaft have a shearing stress of 14 000 psi. Determine the force acting at the pulley that will shear the key.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
]